Brotherhood Wine Company Records, 1822-2006
Brotherhood Wine Company Records
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Brotherhood Wine Company Records 1822-2004.
6701
10 cubic ft.
Memorabilia, Newspapers, Photographs, Printed Materials, Publications
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Brotherwood Wine Company ephemera, including brochures, newspaper clippings, and other printed material
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
The Brotherhood winery was established by a European emigre, John Jaques, who produced the first commercial vintage in 1839 under the label "Blooming Grove Winery". Brotherhood has been in continuous operation since that time. In 1858 the property and winery was deeded to Mr. Jaques' three sons, John Jr, Oren, and Charles, and renamed "Jacques Brothers' Winery". In 1886, Charles, the last surviving brother, sold the winery to a father and son, Jesse M. and Edward R. Emerson. They renamed the winery Brotherhood. Jesse Emerson and his son expanded the facility, adding the "landmark" stone building with additional underground cellars that are the largest in the country. Edward, who was author of "The Story of the Vine", was in control of the winery in 1919 when prohibition was enacted. Having survived prohibition by the sale of sacramental wine, the winery again changed ownership around 1921. Louis Farrell and his son Louis L. Jr acquired a controlling interest in the Brotherhood Winery and ran it until 1947 when Louis Farrell Sr. died. His son died shortly thereafter, and the Winery was then managed by three Farrell cousins, one of whom, Francis Farrell, led the Winery into the post-WWII era. The winery underwent dramatic changes - major expansion, the beginning of a visitor tour operation and the creation of a broad range of award-winning wines. Brotherhood remained a "family business" until a change of ownership in January of 1987. Brotherhood Winery is listed in the New York State Register of Historic Places and is listed as a National Historic Landmark and uses the slogan "America's Oldest Winery".
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
This collection documents the winery business through ledgers and account books (1920 - 1958); press clippings; scrapbooks; artwork; labels; event posters; photographs of staff, operations and events; price sheets; subject files; licensing files; PR and marketing files; and administrative documents. Also some personal correspondence from those involved with the winery.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Beaza, Cesar E.; Diehl, Adelaide L.; Diehl, Herman A.; Emerson, Edward R. (Edward Randolph), b. 1856.; Emerson, Idanthea De Lacey.; Emerson, Jesse M.; Farrell, Francis L.; Farrell, Louis L.; Jaques, John b.1770.; Kedem's Wine Cellars.; Gold Seal Winery.; Pleasant Valley Wine Company.; Taylor Wine Company.; Winged Foot Golf Club.
Subjects:
Distilleries--Law and legislation.; Grape industry.; Grape industry--New York (State).; License system.; Liquor industry.; Liquor laws.; Viticulture.; Viticulture--New York (State).; Wine bottles.; Wine--Marketing.; Wine and wine making.; Wine and wine making--Argentina.; Wine and wine making--California; Wine and wine making--Chile.; Wine and wine making--France.; Wine and wine making--Germany.; Wine and wine making--Italy.; Wine and wine making--New York (State).; Wine and wine making--Portugal.; Wine and wine making--Spain.; Wine and wine making--United States.
Places:
Hudson River Valley (N.Y. and N.J.); Washingtonville (N.Y.)
INFORMATION FOR USERS
Access Restrictions:
If existing, 10 year restriction on administrative records; 25 year restriction on financial records of the current company; 75 year restriction on any wine formulations.
Copyrighted material requires the approval of Brotherhood Wine Company for publication.
NOTES
Forms part of the Eastern Wine and Grape Archive. (EWGA)
RELATED MATERIALS
See also the book The Story of Brotherhood, America's Oldest Winery by Robert Bedford.
SERIES LIST
Series I. General
Boxes: 1, 3, 4, 5, 6
Series II. Photographs
Box: 1
Series III. Correspondence
Box: 2
Series IV. Subject File
Box: 3
Series V. Wine Regulation and License File
Box: 4
Series VI. Scrapbooks
Boxes: 7, 8
Series VII. Ledger Books
Boxes: 8, 9, 10, 11, 12
CONTAINER LIST
- Series I. General (Box 1, 3, 4, 5, 6)
  - Histories of Brotherhood from employees, 1995, 2003 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Includes employees who worked from 1938-1948 and 1938-1941. Also letter from Baeza recognizing the death of Edward Jaques McLaughlin.
  - Copy of an overview of Brotherhood winery history., 1989-2004 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    Also transcript from the Congressional Record of a May 17, 1989 House of Representatives session in which Representative Benjamin A. Gilman mentions the 150th anniversary of Brotherhood. Also copy of a May 16, 2000 letter from Ruth L. Pierpont acknowledging the winery's listing on the National Register of Historic Places. List of Brotherhood winemakers. Ca. 2004 price list.
  - John Jaques personal papers, 1824 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    Includes supply invoices and Jaques Brothers sales brochure from ca 1860. Material found in the wall of a house during a remodel.
  - Daily diary, includes wine notes and weather notes., 1861 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Sales literature and ephemera., 1875-1904 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    Includes Price list from 1875, 1891, 1904 color reproductions of some items made from the CD that is included in the collection.
  - Brotherhood checks, 1866, 1901 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Bylaws of Brotherhood, 1907 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - United States Internal Revenue gauger's daily report, 1917 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Administrative documents regarding Idanthea Emerson's Will and alcohol tax unit, and a Brotherhood Christmas card., 1940-1943 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - CD of images, 1899, 1900, 1978, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    Contains scans of 1899 price booklet, assorted 1900 ephemera items, 1900 brochure with information about a trip to Washington to discuss the champagne making process and purity with the Senate, several 1989 photos, 1978 port label.
  - Wine sample analysis book., 1958-1976 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Wine Bottle Labels, 1869-1950s (Box 1, Folder 12)
    Includes Brotherhood Corporation, Jerusalem Wines, and Goshen Inn
  - Assorted wine bottle lables, not all from Brotherhood, 1910s-1930s (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Brotherhood wine bottle labels, Bulk 1980s-1990s (Box 1, Folder 14)
    Includes Japanese market labels.
  - Brotherhood wine bottle labels, 1960s-1990s (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Advertising, artwork for publications, proofs, 1960s-2000s (Box 1, Folder 16)
    Also see Boxes 5 and 6
  - Advertising, includes booklet on how to create advertising that sells from Ogilvy & Mather., 1960s-2000s (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Brotherhood press kit, 2006 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Winery sketches by E. J. McGlaugin, undated (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Certificate for Dissolution of Brotherhood Wine Company, includes letter of terms., 1922, 1931 (Box 1, Folder 47)
  - Event entertainment brochures and information, includes fireworks, singers, Up With People, ticketing. Includes Give a Wine Tasting Party brochure, also available as TP548.5.A5 N49 1966., 1950s-80s (Box 3, Folder 1, 2)
  - Hot air baloon company information, includes Boland Baloon and Fantasy Ballon Flights Inc., 1980s (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Catering information, includes Fabulous Foods Inc., 1980s (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Lobster Classic, 1984 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - A Day's Getaway promotion, 1985 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - A Day at the Races promotion, 1986 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Wine tour information, 1989 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Counrty Cycling Tours, 1986 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Associated Hudson Valley tourism industry brochures collected by Brotherhood, 1990s-2000s (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Newspaper clippings containing Brotherhood advertisements, 1968-1969 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - 1991, Japanese market press (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Press releases, brochures, 1960s-1970s (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Press releases, 1982 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Press releases, 1983 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Orange County New York advertising correspondence, 1985-1986 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Eloise D. Farrell personal correspondence, 1979 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Dillon Gordon ad agency advertisements, includes radio spots, 1976 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Genghis Khan ginseng wine advertisements and promotional material label, 1989 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Product information on Calesa Vina and Schapiro's Kosher wines., 2002 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Brochures, product descriptions, awards listing, 1970s-2000s (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Photocopies of articles, clippings, product information, 1980s-1990s (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Large information sales brochures for retailers and restaurants, ca. 1960 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Bottle toppers, wine product cards, 1970s-1980s (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - "Custom labels" binder, 1995-1999 (Box 4, Folder 16)
    Information regarding custom labeling.
  - Real estate listing package about the winery., ca. 1987 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Packet about the winery for sales representatives., April 30, 2004 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Press kit for the 150th anniversary., 1989 (Box 4, Folder 19)
    Includes photocopied press clippings, photo of Cesar Baeza, labels and descriptions for the entire product line, photocopies of a letter and certificate from the American Wine Society presenting a silver medal from a competition.
  - Situation analysis and strategic recommendation report compiled by Seaward Associates Inc., June 23, 1987 (Box 4, Folder 20)
    Covers all aspects of the wineries operations and gives suggestions for the future.
  - Brotherhood Winery Project. Consultation report on winery operations., April 21, 1992 (Box 4, Folder 21)
    Appears unprofessionally done, perhaps a school project. Written by someone named Warren. Includes recommendations for the future.
  - Grape sales, 1990 (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Misc. items, includes employee list, 1990s (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - Wine tasting theme party invitations, 1972-1979 (Box 4, Folder 41)
  - News clippings., 1979-2000s (Box 4, Folder 42)
  - Oversized items, posters, advertising,, artwork proofs for publications., 1960s-1980s (Box 5)
  - Oversized items, posters, advertising, news article, artwork proofs for publications. Also blueprints for the winery., 1936, 1951, 1970s-1990s (Box 6)
- Series II. Photographs (Box 1)
  Photos of people include John J. Gleason August 1938, Lester Pee Wee Alexander, Hampton Hall, Hamilton Hall, Joseph Nemeth, Chester Rusclinski, Tom Quinn, Elsie, Brenda MacMillan, Diane Newlander, Joseph Monostori, Cesar Baeza. One of the early photo folders contains an envelope with cards that have biographical information regarding some of the employees in the photos. Champagne finishing room 1904, older photos, photocopies of photos, photos from wine tours, some marked for publication, some with descriptions, winery equipment, winemaster Capitol sales meeting 4-30-76, photos of events ca. 2000, product photos, operations, etc. Includes negatives and contact sheets.
  - Early photos, ca. 1900s-1940s (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Photos ca. 1950s-1970s, ca. 1950s-1970s (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Wine master Joe Monostori, ca. 1968 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Winery operations, includes barrels, cask cleaning., 1950s-1970s (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Champagne equipment and bottling, ca 1950s-1960s (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - WOR-AM radio personalities at Brotherhood, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Gloria Okun cooking at Brotherhood, includes recipes, ca. 1976 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Promotional photos of Diane Newlander, Brenda McMillan, and Rebecca J. Baxter at Brotherhood, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Photos for winery brochure, ca. 1960 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Color photos of winery operations, some with captions, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Color photos of winery and events, 1970s (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Events, includes Harvest Grape Festival, people, 1950s-1970s (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Norwegian (Norway) Councilate and Lions Club event at Brotherhood, ca. 1965 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Event photos, ca. 2000s (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Exterior photos of the winery, 1950s-1970s (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Photos removed from scrapbooks, ca 1970s (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Misc. photo negatives, ca 1965-1975 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Negatives of a store bottle display, ca. 1965 (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Photocopies of photos (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Christmas decorating contest, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Christmas event, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - Personal photos, includes tennis event, craft shop candle and sign maker, Gasho Farm House resteraunt, 1960s-1970s (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - Brotherhood booth at a fair, possibly the New York State Fair, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - Promotional photos of retailers and wine stores, ca. 1976 (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - Photos ca. 1980s-1990s, ca. 1980s-1990s (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - Photos of Old Grape Press (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - Cesar Baeza Photo, ca. 1990 (Box 1, Folder 46)
- Series III. Correspondence (Box 2)
  Loose letterbook copies of correspondence from Louis L. Farrell from 1920s-1940s. Includes some originals of incoming correspondence. Appears incomplete. Some letters are marked as from the President of Brotherhood others are marked as from Vice President, letters marked Vice President may be from Louis Farrell Jr.
  Letterbook pages are acidic and very fragile. Handle with care. Folders titled by letter are not in any order. Folders titled with a specific name are arranged in reverse chronologic order. For these folders please maintain correct date order when viewing.
  - A-B (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - C (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Henry Casademont and Leocadie Casademont, 1926-1939 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    Leocadie appears to be Louis' sister.
  - Joseph Conlon and Margaret Conlon, 1935-1940 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Covington, Burling, & Rublee, Marion P. Wormhoudt, 1927 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    Letters discuss the distribution of Brotherhood stock owned by Edward R. Emerson to his wife. Includes a distribution check showing the amount the estate of E. R. Emerson received. Also included is a page describing how Brotherhood stock is valued. Letters have mention of a Mrs. Moffat as well.
  - D-E (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Adelaide L. Diehl, 1930-1936 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    Adelaide appears to be Louis' sister.
  - Adelaide L. Diehl, 1925-1929 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Herman A. Diehl and Herman A. Diehl Jr., 1931-1935 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Herman A. Diehl and Herman A. Diehl Jr., 1930 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Edward R. Emerson, 1924-1926 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Idanthea de la Vergne de Lacey Emerson, 1930-1938 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Idanthea de la Vergne de Lacey Emerson, 1927-1929 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    Mrs. Edward R. Emerson.
  - Idanthea de la Vergne de Lacey Emerson, 1924-1926 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Jesse M. Emerson and Florence L. Emerson, 1924-1928 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - F-G (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - F. L. Farrell and Nellie Farrell., 1928-1932 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Louis L. Farrell Jr., 1928-1932 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - James W. Flanagan, 1924-1944 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - John S Gleason and Alma Gleason, 1926 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - John S. Gleason, July-December 1925 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - John S. Gleason, January-June 1925 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - H-K (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - L-M (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - George Lynch, 1927-1936 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - L. M. Martini Grape Products, 1936-1939 (Box 2, Folder 26)
    L. M. Martini. Letters discuss orders, sacramental wine specifics, dealings with clergy on getting approval of wines, rules of the Catholic Church pertaining to wine.
  - Jessie Emerson Moffat, 1931-1946 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - N-P (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - F. A. Pelligrino, 1935-1938 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Q-R (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - S (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Al H. Schilling, 1925-1933 (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Scott and Sneed Attorneys and Counselors at Law and J. Bradley Scott, 1925-1927 (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - E. M. Sheehan & Company Merchandisng Agents, 1922 (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - A. H. Sweeny and Van Alsyne, Noel, and Company Inc., 1925-1934 (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - T (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - U-V (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - W (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - Wingate & Cullen, 1923-1930 (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - Winged Foot Golf Club, 1927-1935 (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - Law Offices of Wise & Ottenberg, 1934-1945 (Box 2, Folder 41)
    Mostly regarding mortgages and property. Irving Ottenberg, Benedict S. Wise, Agnes Bradley.
  - Law Offices of Wise & Ottenberg, 1925-1933 (Box 2, Folder 42)
  - Older letterbook copies mostly letter K and J., 1901-1902 (Box 2, Folder 43-47)
  - Miscellaneous letterbook copy pages, bank receipts (Box 2, Folder 48)
- Series IV. Subject File (Box 3, Folder 10-54)
  - Almadén Winery, 1970s (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Argentina - Argentine wines, 1970s (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Bear Mountain Winery, 1970s (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Benmarl Vineyards, 1970s (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Bottles and Jug Wines, 1970s (Box 3, Folder 14)
    Includes Jacquin's four compartment bottle, coffee pot bottle, articles, Julius Wile Sons & Co. Inc
  - Brotherhood Winery History and Information, 1970s (Box 3, Folder 15)
    Includes handwritten drafts for publications.
  - Bully Hill and Keuka Lake Wine, 1970s (Box 3, Folder 16)
    Includes Walter S. Taylor, Fingerlakes Wine Museum, Winemaker's Shop, Lake Keuka Wine Company, Pleasant Valley Wine Company, Greyton H. Taylor Wine Museum.
  - California Wine Articles, 1970s (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Californian Wines, brochures, product information, 1970s (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Canadian Society of Oenologists, 1970s (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Catawba Grapes, Widmer Winery, 1970s (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Champagne, 1950s-1970s (Box 3, Folder 21)
    Includes Taittinger and Taylor Wine Company.
  - Europe European Wines Miscellaneous, 1970s (Box 3, Folder 22)
    Includes Yugoslavia, Hungary, Greece.
  - France - French Wines, 1970s (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Germany - German Wines, 1970s (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Gold Seal Winery, 1973 (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Great Western Wine Company, 1950s-1970s (Box 3, Folder 26)
    Also includes Pleasant Valley Wine Company.
  - Hudson River Valley Wineries, 1970s (Box 3, Folder 27)
    Includes Great River Winery.
  - Hudson Valley Wine Company, 1970s (Box 3, Folder 28)
    Includes Mark Miller, Benmarl Vineyards, and Hudson River Valley Association, now Regent Champagne Cellars.
  - Italy - Italian Wines, 1970s (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - Kedem Winery, 1970s (Box 3, Folder 30)
    Includes Royal Wine Corporation, Kosher wines, Pleasant Valley Wine Company, Great Western.
  - Konstantin Frank Vinifera Wine Cellars, 1975 (Box 3, Folder 31)
    Includes information on Willy Frank.
  - Largest in U.S. Wineries, 1977, 1980 (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - Liquor and Spirits Brochures and Information, 1970s (Box 3, Folder 33)
    Includes Hiram Walker, Seagram's, Tanqueray, Sake, W. A. Taylor and Co., Thomas Hine and Company Jarnac Cognac Brandy.
  - May Wine Advertising flyers, 1970s (Box 3, Folder 34)
  - Miscellaneous Wine and Spirit information, 1970s (Box 3, Folder 35)
    Includes articles, clippings, retailer brochures, ephemera. Esposito's, Barry Wine Company, Boordy Vineyards, Frederick S. Johnson Estate Wines, Herman A. Kluxen Wines of New Jersey, Munson Shaw, His Majesty's Spirits, Coleman & Company, Schieffelin, Domecq, Brotherhood, Wine Growing and Wine Types.
  - Packaging, 1970s (Box 3, Folder 36)
  - Patent Registration Requests, 1965-1970 (Box 3, Folder 37)
    Includes Buchman & Buchman Law Offices.
  - Pennsylvania Wines and Spirits, 1970s (Box 3, Folder 38)
  - Portugal - Portuguese Wines, Port, 1970s (Box 3, Folder 39)
  - Spain - Spanish Wines, Sherry, 1970s (Box 3, Folder 40)
  - Taylor Wine Company, 1970s (Box 3, Folder 41)
    Includes Greyton Hoyt Taylor Wine Museum.
  - Village of Washingtonville, 1970s (Box 3, Folder 42)
  - Washingtonville Board of Trade, 1970s (Box 3, Folder 43)
  - Washingtonville Little League, 1970s (Box 3, Folder 44)
  - Washingtonville Police Department, 1970s (Box 3, Folder 45)
  - Washingtonville Village Board, 1970s (Box 3, Folder 46)
  - Widmer's Wine Cellars, 1965-72 (Box 3, Folder 47)
  - Wines & Vines and Wine Institute Publications, 1970s (Box 3, Folder 48)
    Includes 1975 Wines & Vines directory listing for Brotherhood
  - Wine Articles, 1957, 1964, 1972-1976, 1990s (Box 3, Folder 49)
    Includes booklet The Wines of the East The Hybrids by Hudson Catell and H. Lee Stauffer.
  - Wine Descriptions, 1970s (Box 3, Folder 50)
    Includes text for a draft wine lecture.
  - Wine Dispensers, 1970s (Box 3, Folder 51)
  - Wine Racks, 1970s (Box 3, Folder 52)
    Racks for home and business. Includes the Wine Well.
  - Wine Newspaper Clippings, 1970s (Box 3, Folder 53)
    Some clippings mention Brotherhood
  - Wine Talk, 1974-1978, 1992 (Box 3, Folder 54)
    Clippings from a column from the New York Times by Frank J. Prial, Widmer mentioned in one article.
- Series V. Wine Regulation and License File (Box 4, Folder 24-40)
  Wine regulations, liquor laws, forms, press clippings and other licensing information organized by State. Also Brotherhood specific forms, licenses, and liquor control offices correspondence.
  - Notes mentioning States to be included for proposed marketing expansion., 1988 (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - Connecticut, 1970s-1980s (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - Delaware, 1970s-1980s (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - Florida, 1970s-1980s (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - Maine, 1970s-1980s (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - Maryland, 1970s-1980s (Box 4, Folder 29)
  - Michigan, 1970s-1980s (Box 4, Folder 30)
  - Nevada, 1970s-1980s (Box 4, Folder 31)
  - New Jersey, 1970s-1980s (Box 4, Folder 32)
  - New York, 1970s-1980s (Box 4, Folder 33)
    Includes Appellation New York State event program, descriptions of other NY Wineries, 1976 and Privileges of NYS Winery License, 1981
  - Ohio, 1950s-1980s (Box 4, Folder 34, 35)
    Includes many Brotherhood wine bottle labels. Department of Liquor Control, correspondence.
  - Rhode Island, 1970s-1980s (Box 4, Folder 36)
  - Vermont, 1970s-1980s (Box 4, Folder 37)
  - Virginia, 1970s-1980s (Box 4, Folder 38)
  - Washington D.C., 1970s-1980s (Box 4, Folder 39)
  - West Virginia, 1970s-1980s (Box 4, Folder 40)
- Series VI. Scrapbooks (Box 7, 8)
  - Binder scrapbook #1, 1966-1970s (Box 7, Folder 1)
    Brochures, event ephemera, holiday promotions, letter regarding production of altar wines from the Archdiocese of New York to Frank L. Farrell, dealer letters and signage, labels, original order retained.
  - Binder scrapbook #2, 1977-1979 (Box 7, Folder 2)
    Event ephemera, wine tour info, brochures, order forms, advertisements, gold card VIP promotion material, original order retained.
  - Binder scrapbook #3, 1977-1989 (Box 7, Folder 3)
    Clippings, event ephemera, winery balloon festival advertising plan, advertisements, original order retained.
  - Disassembled scrapbook (red), 1968 (Box 7, Folder 4)
    Contains newspaper clippings mentioning Brotherhood.
  - Disassembled scrapbook, 1970 (Box 7, Folder 5)
    Contains newspaper clippings mentioning Brotherhood some press releases.
  - Scrapbook (blue Christmas card binder), May - September 1967 (Box 7)
    Clippings, ephemera, etc.
  - Scrapbook (red Christmas card binder), 1968 (Box 7)
  - Scrapbook (blue), 1968-1970 (Box 7)
    Contains holiday letters, brochures, and other ephemera.
  - Scrapbook Publicity (white), 1972 (Box 7)
  - Sales ledger October 1939 - August 1944 and 1960s Scrapbook, October 1939 - August 1944, 1962-1967 (Box 8)
    This item is a ledger that was reused as a scrapbook portfolio for 1960s items. The information contained in the ledger is still mostly legible, but in some places 1960s scrapbook items have been glued in over the ledger text. The scrapbook items include newspaper clippings, and advertising, and other winery ephemera.
- Series VII. Ledger Books (Box 8, 9, 10, 11, 12)